<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.5.dtd">
<mteval>
<refset setid="newssyscombtest2010" srclang="French" trglang="English" refid="reference01">
<doc docid="idnes.cz/2009/12/11/76492" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Lack of snow in mountains causes problems for hoteliers </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> It&apos;s not only Krkonoše ski-lift operators who are worried by these bare slopes. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The lack of snow is putting people off booking ski holidays in hotels and guest houses. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This means vacancies are still available in the Krkonoše throughout the winter, including Christmas and New Year&apos;s Eve. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="5"> We&apos;re getting plenty of visitors to our site. </seg>
<seg id="6"> People are browsing the offers, checking prices, but, so far, are worried about making a definite booking. </seg>
<seg id="7"> &quot;When they call, the first thing they ask is if we think they&apos;ll see snow or mud,&quot; says Martin Jandura, who runs the Spindl.Info information web site. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="8"> Anyone who wants to spend New Year&apos;s Eve in Špindlerův Mlýn just how they want, had better start thinking about booking soon. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Those preferring to save money and go for cheaper accommodation can still give it a few days. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="10"> Hoteliers in Špindlerův Mlýn are so far just offering week-long stays for New Year&apos;s Eve. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I think they&apos;ll try to keep that up for a while, but even they will give in and offer shorter stays. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Then there&apos;ll be a sudden shortage of vacancies,&quot; estimates Jandura. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="13"> The Vrchlabí travel agency Ingtours is still offering vacancies throughout the winter. </seg>
<seg id="14"> What we’re interested in is Christmas week, which hasn&apos;t sold out yet. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Half of our capacity is still available. </seg>
<seg id="16"> That&apos;s why we&apos;ve been preparing some cheaper last-minute Christmas breaks,&quot; said Ingtours director Petr Schiefert. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="17"> The Vrchlabí travel agency can still offer New Year&apos;s Eve in the Krkonoše, but there are fewer vacancies. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Another good time for bookings is the first fortnight in February, although bookings for the remaining winter dates tend to be average. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="19"> This year, interest in winter breaks is low due to the fact that there is still no snow on the Krkonoše. </seg>
<seg id="20"> People are waiting to see if any falls. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Nobody wants to spend the end of the year in the mountains when there&apos;s no snow. </seg>
<seg id="22"> If snow falls on the slopes this week, Christmas will sell out too,&quot; says Schiefert. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="23"> On the other hand, the Horizont Hotel in Pec pod Sněžkou has seen better bookings this year than last year. </seg>
<seg id="24"> We&apos;re up about 5 percent. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="25"> We have the last few vacancies for New Year&apos;s Eve and Christmas. </seg>
<seg id="26"> There&apos;s a lot of interest during the Polish holidays in January and we usually get plenty of bookings in February too,&quot; explains the director of the best hotel in Pec, Karel Rada. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="27"> The Omnia Hotel, by the central car park in Janské Lázně, is eighty-percent booked up for New Year&apos;s Eve. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Yet the newest hotel in Janské Lázně still has half its beds free for Christmas. </seg>
<seg id="29"> January this year has been a nice surprise, as we&apos;re already sixty-percent booked up. </seg>
<seg id="30"> So February isn&apos;t looking quite so good, but as soon as it snows, then interest in staying in the Krkonoše will definitely rise, says the owner of the Omnia Hotel, Erik Sporysch. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="31"> For now, however, the Krkonoše hoteliers will have to wait for heavier falls of snow. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Colder weather is forecast for Thursday, so if anything falls, it should be snow. </seg>
<seg id="33"> But it should get warmer again after that, said Jiří Jakubský of the Czech Hydrometeorological Institute in Hradec. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75519" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> USA: Repetition is the mother of wisdom </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> It&apos;s almost funny to see how Barack Obama, reputedly the wisest president, is trying so hard in the matter of the Afghan war to repeat the strategy of his predecessor, having himself considered him to be the most foolish. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="3"> When he finally came out with his long-awaited Afghan doctrine, it appeared that he had made a carbon copy of Bush&apos;s Iraq scenario three years earlier. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It&apos;s not just that in the text itself he repeatedly uses the words &quot;just like in Iraq&quot;, but he even went as far as to use the name of Bush&apos;s declaration from January 2007 as the title of his own declaration:&quot;The new way forward&quot;. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="5"> While three years ago he himself criticised Bush&apos;s idea to send fresh troops to help in the beleaguered civil war in Iraq as &quot;an irresponsible decision with catastrophic consequences&quot;. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The following months, however, showed that Bush&apos;s strategy, which was recommended by his field commanders, was the only possible course of action and so successful that there are no reports in the news about Iraq. </seg>
<seg id="7"> It didn&apos;t help Bush&apos;s reputation, but in objective terms, it left his successor in a much more favourable position than might be expected. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Barack Obama hopes that, in Afghanistan, the miracle will repeat itself. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="9"> He was again asked to increase the military contingent by his field commanders, particularly the supreme commander of the Afghan operation General Stanley McChrystal, who even went against the custom of his subordinates to harshly criticise the reluctant gunners in the White House. </seg>
<seg id="10"> He asked for 40 thousand men to turn the situation around. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The president hesitated for three months, but failed to come up with anything better, and so at least the general did out of 10 thousand soldiers. </seg>
<seg id="12"> He managed to squeeze a promise out of Europe for another 5 thousand, even though he himself was originally counting on 10. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="13"> The trickiest aspect of Obama&apos;s strategy seems to be his plan to start pulling troops out of Afghanistan within 18 months and to finish the process within three years. Obama&apos;s doctrine as a whole calls for more questions than it answers. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Many doubt that this half-hearted increase will bear the same fruit as the action plan in Iraq. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Despite the internecine war of recent years, Iraqi society is relatively firm on its feet and its leaders have been honouring the treaties. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="16"> The Afghan situation is just the opposite - nobody can be relied upon and no treaties are being upheld. </seg>
<seg id="17"> In these conditions, it is hard for the Afghan security forces to prepare, being so used to changing leaders to suit themselves. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Political institutions, no matter how formally they might be set up, will be nothing more than a Potemkin village in which patriarchal tribal relations will run wild. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Balancing the interests of a variety of ethnic groups is unusually difficult due to the tricky relations between them, a fact which is further complicated by the influence of Pakistan and Iran. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Even building an &quot;operational state&quot;, which is the most basic aim of the entire operation, does not seem particularly feasible. </seg>
<seg id="21"> The timing of Obama&apos;s strategy is foiled by his voluntarism. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Over the last eight years, the situation in Afghanistan has just gotten worse and worse, and is now on the verge of exploding. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Only a truly romantic soul, totally unaffected by reality, could believe that the soldiers sent into the turmoil of this war for an &quot;early return home&quot; will bring about any miracles here. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="24"> From a political viewpoin,t it is pure irresponsibility setting a date for withdrawing the troops, as the Taliban will see it as indirect acknowledgement of an American defeat. </seg>
<seg id="25"> The last NATO summit showed that the willingness of the European people to take part in the operations in Afghanistan is waning. </seg>
<seg id="26"> European politicians cannot and are unwilling to explain to voters what the security of Germany or Italy has to do with the war in the foothills of the Hindu Kush. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Another factor which could radically stir things up is what is going on around Iran. </seg>
<seg id="28"> If the situation continues to get worse and increased sanctions against Iran have no effect, the United States will face the difficult question of whether to try to resolve the situation using military force or not. </seg>
<seg id="29"> This will need answering when, according to Obama, America orders the victorious withdrawal of its troops from Afghanistan. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="30"> Any such solution will obviously also mean a dramatic turnaround in the Afghan situation. </seg>
<seg id="31"> The only saving grace for Barack Obama is the fact that there are three more years to the presidential elections, so there&apos;s still enough time for him to come up with another strategyif this one turns out to be a total whitewash. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75501" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Managers at Goldman Sachs no longer to receive cash bonuses </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> The top management of the American bank Goldman Sachs will not receive their bonuses in cash this year. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The announcement came from the company as a reaction to the harsh criticism of their salary policies. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="4"> Instead of money, the group of 30 top managers will receive shares, which cannot be sold for another five years. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The shares can also be confiscated if the managers take excessive risks. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="6"> According to Reuters, Goldman Sachs is leading the effort to link Wall Street bonuses with long-term performance. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I assume that Wall Street is well aware of the broader path it has to take, said former investment banker for JPMorgan, Douglas Elliott. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The problem lies in the details, he added. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="9"> Goldman Sachshas been targeted by critics since it set aside almost 17 billion dollars (almost 300 billion crowns) for bonuses in the first three quarters of this year. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Reuters claims that the total bonuses awarded by the business this year, despite today&apos;s announcement, exceeds 20 billion dollars. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="11"> High bonuses in the banking sector, what with the economic crisis, have become a political hot potato. </seg>
<seg id="12"> On Wednesday, Britain announced that it had decided to charge a one-off fifty percent tax rate on bankers&apos; bonuses exceeding 25,000 pounds (around 712,000 CZK). </seg>
<seg id="13"> France is preparing similar measures. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75493" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> This year, women were awarded the Nobel Prize in all fields except physics </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> In Stockholm today, a record five women received Nobel Prizes from the Swedish king Carl XVI Gustaf in the professional categories and for literature. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In addition to four scientists, they also included the German writer Herta Müller, originally from Romania. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="4"> The Nobel Prize for medicine went to two American biologists, Elizabeth Blackburn and Carol Greider, together with their fellow countryman Jack Szostak, for their research in chromosomes. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The prize for chemistry was won by the Israeli Ada Jonath, together with the Americans Venkatraman Ramakrishnan and Thomas Steitz, for their work to clarify the structure and function of ribosomes. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="6"> The last award was the Nobel Prize for Economics, which went to the Americans Elinor Ostrom and Oliver Williamson for their analysis of economic management. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="7"> The only specialised category which nobody won this year was physics. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Today, this prize was won by the scientists Charles Kao, for his research in optical fibres, and George Smith and Willard Boyle, for inventing the CCD ship, which is the basis for all digital cameras, faxes, and astronomical telescopes. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="9"> All the winners received a diploma, the Nobel Medal, and a certificate for a monetary reward. </seg>
<seg id="10"> In each category, this award totals ten million Swedish krona (approximately 25 million CZK). </seg>
<seg id="11"> If there are multiple winners, they share the prize money between them. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="12"> Traditionally, the most highly-anticipated award, the Nobel Peace Prize, went to the American president Barack Obama in the Norwegian city of Oslo this afternoon. </seg>
<seg id="13"> In his speech, he acknowledged that the award was controversial, as he is just starting out in office and, moreover, heads a country which is currently at war in two countries - Iraq and Afghanistan. </seg>
<seg id="14"> In defence of his policy he added, however, that these wars were essential in order to bring about peace, despite the high cost. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75487" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Minister Janota considers resignation. Klaus invites him to the Castle </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> On Friday morning, President Václav Klaus will meet with the finance minister Eduard Janota, who is considering resigning as he does not agree with the government&apos;s budget for next year as approved on Wednesday by the Chamber of Deputies. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It is assumed that the budget and also Janota&apos;s possible continuation in office will be the topic of Friday&apos;s meeting. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The budget has also been criticised by Klaus. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He claims the deficit is too high, which is worsening the public funding crisis. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="6"> The meeting was announced by the president&apos;s spokesman Radim Ochvat. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Janota wants to discuss his future on Monday with the Prime Minister, Jan Fischer. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="8"> According to the Budget Act, which Klaus is due to sign, the Czech Republic should get by with a deficit of 163 billion crowns. </seg>
<seg id="9"> However, on Wednesday, the House approved the left&apos;s proposals to transfer funds, gave state employees a pay rise, and allocated extra money for social services and for direct payments to farmers. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The government criticised the social democrats&apos; proposals, saying that they will surreptitiously increase the budget deficit. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="11"> A bitter political dispute has broken out between the left on the one hand, and the government, Klaus, and the right on the other, leading to questions about the future of Fischer&apos;s interim government, which was agreed on in spring by the ODS, ČSSD and Green Party. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Critics claim that the budget, as approved by the House, essentially does away with the package of saving measures put into effect by Fischer&apos;s government in autumn and which it believes should stop the state falling deeper into debt. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="13"> At a breakfast meeting with entrepreneurs today, Klaus, who is behind the state budget law but is not obliged to sign it, declared that politicians have long been neglecting a &quot;serious problem,&quot; which is the &quot;unsustainable deficit level&quot; of public finances. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Now, he claims, there is no good solution to this. </seg>
<seg id="15"> The only thing that could improve the situation is a strong government which could fall back on the broader consensus of the political parties, the president says. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="16"> ODS chairman Mirek Topolánek said that it was a terrible budget and that the government should rethink continuing in office. </seg>
<seg id="17"> The vice-chairman of the ODS, Petr Nečas, told ČTK that the concept of an interim government supported by the ČSSD, ODS, and the Green Party is evidently no longer working. </seg>
<seg id="18"> In response to this, Premier Fischer described this statement as &quot;strong words.&quot; </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="19"> The head of the ČSSD, Jiří Paroubek, reacted to Topolánek by saying that what was terrible was the deficit in the budget prepared by the former Topolánek government for this year, which exceeds 200 billion crowns. </seg>
<seg id="20"> On Wednesday the ČSSD declared the approval of next year&apos;s budget to be a success. </seg>
<seg id="21"> The People&apos;s Party was also satisfied. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
</refset>
</mteval>
