<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.5.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="newssyscombtest2010" srclang="French" trglang="English" sysid="maryland">
<doc docid="idnes.cz/2009/12/11/76492" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The lack of snow  concern the hotel </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> The trails deserted  problem to operators of lifts. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The lack of snow  book their stays in hotels and pensions. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Of this, it is still possible  for all dates in winter, including Christmas and new year. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="5"> We have a lot of visits  site. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Internet travel offers prices but dare not commit to reserve for the moment. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And if they call, they ask  there will be snow or mud at Christmas, &quot;said Martin Jandura, operator of Spindl.info. information portal </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="8"> If we want to spend New Year of his dreams to Špindlerův Mlýn, better is no longer hesitate to book. </seg>
<seg id="9"> If the priority is given to economies and that the quality of accommodation only then, we can try to wait a few more days. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="10"> The Špindler hotel offer for the moment that stays of one week for the new year. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I think that they will try again a moment of the place, but they Cèderont them and accept shorter periods. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And then the number of rooms free will quickly, &quot;said Jandura. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="13"> The tourism Ingtours Agency of  free beds for all periods of winter. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The week of Christmas we are most concerned for the moment, it is not completely sold. </seg>
<seg id="15"> There are still free, say, half  our offer. </seg>
<seg id="16"> That is why we have already prepared a few last minute Christmas stays cheaper, &quot;said the director of Ingtours Petr Schiefert. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="17"> The tourism agency of Vrchlabí  new year to Krkonoše, but there are fewer places free. </seg>
<seg id="18"> The first fourteen days of February go well, the remaining winter trips sell moderately. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="19"> This year, interest for  been negatively influenced by the fact that there is still no snow to Krkonoše. </seg>
<seg id="20"> The people expect that it will start to fall. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Nobody wants to spend the winter untain without snow. </seg>
<seg id="22"> If the trails cover during the week, Christmas also will be complete, &quot;think Schiefert. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="23"> In contrast, the occupation of the hotel Horizont CI pod Sněžkou is slightly higher than last year. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It was an improvement of almost five percent. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="25"> We still last few places for the new year as for Christmas. </seg>
<seg id="26"> There is a great interest during the holidays of January of selling well, &quot;inform Karel Rada, Director of best hotel CI. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="27"> The Omnia Hotel near the parking central Jánské Lázně is also full to eighty percent during the new year period. </seg>
<seg id="28"> On the contrary, half the beds remain empty at Christmas in  Lázně. </seg>
<seg id="29"> This year, we have been pleasantly , where we already have sixty percent of occupation at the moment. </seg>
<seg id="30"> February is a little more low at the moment, but as soon as snow will fall, the interest for the Krkonoše still enlarging certainly indicated the Director of the hotel Omnia, Erik Sporysch. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="31"> The hotel Krkonoše must not however hope more snow. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Thursday it will more costs and if there are precipitation, they should be snowy mountain. </seg>
<seg id="33"> But by the time should be warm, inform Jiří Jakubský of Hradec station of the Czech Hydrometeorological Institute. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75519" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> United States: repetition is mother of wisdom </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> It becomes even comic, conscientious effort with which Barack Obama, President to the reputation of wise, reproduces the strategy of his predecessor on the Afghan question, he considered himself very simple. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="3"> When he eventually leave sweat its doctrine so eagerly awaited, it emerged that he had Recopied carbon paper since the Iraq scenario of Bush three years ago. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Not content to use in the text several times the expression &quot;as in Iraq&quot;, he has not hesitated, that is, to use the title of the January 2007 speech by Bush as the title of his own speech: &quot;a new road before&quot; </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="5"> At the same time, he has personally criticised the idea of Bush to send new reinforcements in Iraq consumed by the civil war as &quot;irresponsible and a disastrous decision in its consequences.&quot; </seg>
<seg id="6"> The following months have however shown that Bush ’ s strategy, which stemmed from recommendations of the campaigns commanders, was the only possible and likely success to the point that the newspapers at the moment do not speak at all of Iraq. </seg>
<seg id="7"> This has not improved the Bush reputation, objectively speaking, it has left to his successor a final situation much more favourable than we might hope. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Barack Obama hope that in Afghanistan, the miracle will happen </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="9"> They are again the commanders of campaigns that have requested an increase of military contingent, including the Afghan operation commander, General Stanley Mccristal, who has severely criticised the reluctance of the White House despite the habits of subordination. </seg>
<seg id="10"> He asked 40 000 men in order to make the situation more favourable. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The President has hesitated for three months but in the absence of a better alternative, at least it has defrauded the general 10 000 soldiers. </seg>
<seg id="12"> He has managed to extricate the promise of additional 5 000 from the Europe, even if there were over 10 000. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="13"> This causes the most problems throughout the strategy of Obama seems to be its intention to withdraw military forces from Afghanistan within 18 months and to complete this whole process by three years. The doctrine of Obama brings more questions than it answers. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Many doubt the fact that an increase of half will bring the same fruit that progress in Iraq. </seg>
<seg id="15"> In spite of fratricidal wars in recent years, the Iraqi society is relatively well organised and its leaders honour the agreements. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="16"> The Afghan situation stands by the exact opposite - we cannot rely on person and no treaty is respected. </seg>
<seg id="17"> In these conditions, difficult to prepare Afghan security forces, used to change leader from day to day depending on what suits them. </seg>
<seg id="18"> The political institutions, although based formally remain that the smokescreen behind which will proliferate patriarchal ethnic relations. </seg>
<seg id="19"> It is particularly complex balancing the interests of various ethnic groups given the lack of clarity about the reports, which are still complicated by the Pakistani and Iranian influences. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Even the foundation of a &quot;state quick to act &apos;, which is the aim of the operation, does not seem to be very real. </seg>
<seg id="21"> The time horizon of the Obama strategy makes perplexed by his proactive. </seg>
<seg id="22"> In the past eight years, the situation in Afghanistan has deteriorated and is currently on the brink of chaos. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Only a heart purely romantic and out of reality can be persuaded that the small soldiers sent in the clamour of war in view of their &quot;quick return to the home&quot; will bring a real miracle. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="24"> From a political point of view, fix a date for the withdrawal of troops is purely irresponsible because the Taliban will see us as the indirect admission of defeat. </seg>
<seg id="25"> The last NATO summit showed that in military operations in Afghanistan is moving towards the negative. </seg>
<seg id="26"> The European political or do not want to explain to their electorate in what the security in Germany or Italy is linked to a war in the mountains of the Hindu Kush. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Another factor capable of radically alter of events related to Iran. </seg>
<seg id="28"> If the situation continues to deteriorate and the reinforced sanctions do not have effects on the Iranians, the Americans find themselves faced with the very difficult issue of a resolution of the problem by the use of military force. </seg>
<seg id="29"> It must be addressed by example when, according to Obama, America will the victorious withdrawal of troops in Afghanistan. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="30"> Each solution of this kind will however a dramatic reversal of the Afghan situation. </seg>
<seg id="31"> The only patch for Obama is the fact that it remains three years until the presidential elections and therefore there is still enough time to working on a new strategy, if it proves to be a flop. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75501" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The leaders of the bank Goldman Sachs will receive more than premiums in cash </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> The top leaders of the American bank Goldman Sachs employees will receive this year of cash premiums. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The company announced to respond to strong criticism about its practices. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="4"> The group of 30 leaders will receive shares instead of money, that they will not sell before five years. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The actions can be withdrawn to leaders in cases where they would take too many risks. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="6"> According to Reuters, Goldman Sachs arises the rewards with long-term performance to Wall Street. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I assume that Wall Street is well aware need to take, &quot;said the former investment banker Douglas Elliott of JPMorgan </seg>
<seg id="8"> The concern is in the details, he added. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="9"> The bank Goldman Sachs has after set aside almost $17 billion to premiums on the first three quarters of this year. </seg>
<seg id="10"> For the current year, the total amount of premiums is likely to exceed $20 billion in despite the announcement today, according to the Reuters news agency. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="11"> With the arrival of the financial crisis, have become a sensitive political issue in many countries. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The Kingdom announced Wednesday that it intends to affect a single fee of 50% bankers&apos; bonuses exceeding 25,000 books. </seg>
<seg id="13"> The France preparing similar measures. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75493" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> This year the women received the Nobel Prize in all areas except the physical </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> These are five women, a record Stockholm at the hands of the King of Sweden Charles XVI Gustave Nobel Prize in technical disciplines and literature. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Besides the four scientists there was also the German writer of Romanian origin Herta Müller. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="4"> Two American biologists, Elizabeth Blackburn and Carol Greider received with their fellow Jack Szostak the Nobel Prize for medicine for their research in the area of chromosomes. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The prize for chemistry was awarded to the Israeli Ada Jonath with the Americans Venkatraman Ramakrishnan and Thomas Steitz have clarified the structure and function of ribosomes </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="6"> The last winner was awarded the Nobel Prize in economics, US Elinor Ostrom with his countryman Oliver Williamson, for their analysis of economic governance. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="7"> The only technical discipline that had no winner this year was the physical. </seg>
<seg id="8"> This award was presented today scientists Charles Kao for his research in the area of Fibreoptics and George Smith Avecwillard Boyle for their invention of CCD chips, which are currently at the basis of all the digital cameras, fax or refracting telescopes. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="9"> Each winner received the diploma, the Nobel medal and certificate of acquisition of financial reward. </seg>
<seg id="10"> It reached 10 million Swedish crowns in each category. (approximately EUR 1.1 million) </seg>
<seg id="11"> If one of them contains several winners, they share the award among them. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="12"> The much-anticipated Nobel peace prize has already been postponed this afternoon in Oslo, Norway, in US President Barack Obama. </seg>
<seg id="13"> This, in his speech, recognized the controversial nature of its award as it is only at the beginning of their journey and that it is also at the head of a country engaged in two wars, in Iraq and Afghanistan. </seg>
<seg id="14"> In the discharge of its policy he added that in some situations the war is essential to achieve peace, even if the price is high. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="lidovky.cz/2009/12/10/75487" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Minister Janota intends to resign. Klaus has invited to Château </seg>
</hl>
<p>
<seg id="2"> The President Václav Klaus will Friday morning the Finance Minister Eduard Janota, which weighs his stay in government because of his disagreement with the state budget for the next year as it was adopted by the Chamber of Deputies </seg>
<seg id="3"> It is estimated that the budget and perhaps also the position of Janota to Cabinet will be on the agenda of their appointment on Friday. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Klaus also criticised the budget. </seg>
<seg id="5"> According to him, the deficit is too important, widening the public finance crisis. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="6"> It is the presidential spokesman Radim Ochvat has informed of the meeting. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Janota then discuss its service Monday with Prime Minister Jan Fischer. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="8"> According to the legislation on the budget which will be subject to the signing of Klaus, it is a deficit of crowns 163 billion that the Czech Republic should manage. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Nevertheless, the Chamber proposals of the left about transfers of money and has increased the rewards of officials, the operation of social services and direct payments to farmers. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The government accused proposals of the Social Democrats that they would increase the budget deficit in an indirect way. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="11"> For this reason, a violent disagreement arose between left on the one hand, the government, Klaus and right on the other hand, disagreement which calls into question the future of Fischer who had been formed by agreement between the ODS, the Čssd and the Green Party. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The critics claim that the budget, as it has been voted package of savings measures by the Government from Fischer and who must according to stem the indebtedness of the state. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="13"> Klaus, who may ratify the Law on the State budget but that there is no requirement, said today at a breakfast discussion with entrepreneurs, that policies have long neglected the &quot;serious problem&quot; of the &quot;disability Irréfrénable&quot; of public finances. </seg>
<seg id="14"> At present there is, according to him, no positive solution. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Only a strong government could bring an improvement, if it could rely on a broad consensus among the political parties, according to the president. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="16"> The President of the ODS Mirek Topolánek has and that the government should question its existence. </seg>
<seg id="17"> The Vice-President of the ODS Petr Nečas told the Čtk that the idea of a Cabinet administrative supported by the Čssd, ODS and Greens works clearly more. </seg>
<seg id="18"> In its response, the Prime Minister Fischer described such words of &apos;verdicts drastic &quot;. </seg>
</p>
<p>
<seg id="19"> The head of Čssd Jiří Paroubek reacted to deficit for this year by the former government of Topolánek is staggering and that it will exceed 200 billion kronor. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Wednesday, Čssd described success already the ratification of the state budget for the next year. </seg>
<seg id="21"> The Popular Party was also pleased. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>
